## Joseph Ramirez

505-977-4839 3632 Big Cottonwood Ct SE Albuquerque, NM 87105 JJRamirez.com

JosephJRamirezWD@gmail.com GitHub.com/JosephBlu

linkedin.com/in/joseph-ramirez-3b82b4133

	Technical Toolbox
Languages	PHP, HTML, mySQL, CSS, Bootstrap, Xcoder, Angular
Operating Systems	iOS,
Software	GitHub, Safari, Mozilla Firefox, Painter Essentials 5, Concepts, PHP-Storm, mySQL, Silhouette Studio, Adobe PhotoShop Lightroom, Auto Enginuity, Google Applications: Docs, Gmail, Calendar, Maps, Biometrica, Silhouette.
Hardware	Nikon D3300, Seabring Laser Guided Saw, Silhouette Cameo

#### Education

# Central NM Community College (CNM), STEMulus Center, Albuquerque, NM Deep Dive Coding Bootcamp

Certificate of Completion - Web Developer

Expected March 2016

 Currently enrolled in a 10-week Full Stack Web Developer program focusing on the LAMP stack. This program consist of 600 hours of up to date, mobile-first web development education including: immersive, hands-on development of a personal website and working with a simulated development team to create a Capstone project.

#### Central NM Community College (CNM), Albuquerque, NM

Certificate of Completion - Automotive Technology

Completed May 2010

Entering students will study, through lecture and hands-on training, the fundamentals of automotive service, which includes an introduction to automotive systems, and further study in the ASE automotive specialty areas of: brakes, steering and suspension and electrical systems. Automotive Technology students will continue their career preparation by studying the more advanced principles of automotive service and repair, which includes course work in the following ASE specialty areas: Engine Repair, Automatic Transmission, Manual Drive Train, Electrical/Electronic Systems, Heating and Air Conditioning and Engine Performance. Upon completion of the Automotive Technology Certificate program, graduates will be eligible for entry level employment at dealerships and independent repair facilities.

Portfolio

**GigHub** 

January 2017 - Present

- GigHub is a social networking site for bands/musicians, venues, and for users who want to see what local bands are playing or available. For venues, this network will present the opportunity to find bands/musicians in the local area to perform or form contracts to play for a segment of time. For musicians, the network site will give performers the tools to help find the opportunity to deliver their music and also help them create a fan base to help keep their sound traveling.
- The technology that I'am currently using is PhpStorm for the backend and mySQL to create the database to hose our data. For the Data Design segment, our group used Draw.io

#### **Joseph Ramirez Portfolio**

January 2017 - Present

- Joseph Ramirez Portfolio is a personal web page capstone project that is focusing more on the Front-end aspects of Web Development and less on the Back-end. The web page will showcase the past and present web pages and app projects that I have completed or in-progress.
- As of the moment the software I am using is PhpStorm for the Back-end and <u>wireframe.cc</u> for the wire frame of the portfolio.

#### **Blu Bird Tile Art**

September 2015 - Present

- BluBird Tile is a business start up that creates custom tile back splash and private and public mosaic pieces. This website was my first project, although it was primarily Front-end design, I was able to experience some Back-end coding.
- For this website, I used the Wordpress and Composer front-end to create the website.

## Experience

## Fabricator and Installer, Sunwest Granite, Albuquerque, NM

November 2014 - Present

- Used Concept app to create a 2-D layout of where the granite counters will be placed.
- Remotely controlled a Seabring laser-guided Table saw, the table saw cuts granite/quartz slabs accordingly to the template created.

# Security, Laguna Development Corporation, Albuquerque, NM

June 2011 - January 2013

 My job detail involved in operating the BIOmetrica Security Surveillance Intelligence Network (SSIN). This is a surveillance system that controlled the surveillance cameras on the property, including high sensitive areas of the casino. The system also allowed us to keep a record of the logins into the high sensitive areas.

## Joseph Ramirez

JosephJRamirezWD@gmail.com GitHub.com/JosephBlu

505-977-4839 3632 Big Cottonwood Ct SE Albuquerque, NM 87105 JJRamirez.com
linkedin.com/in/joseph-ramirez-3b82b4133

# **Summary**

I am pursuing a new career after years of working in a hard labor occupation. Although i have had different occupations over the years, fabricating and installing granite/quartz countertops has alway been a primary practice. Despite the level of knowledge and experience earned in the granite trade, this occupation did not present the level of challenge desired. While learning new skills, coding captured my attention. I decided to take the risk and joined the Deep Dive Coding Bootcamp, I soon realized that Web and App Development did not only meet my desired level of challenge in problem solving but it